The DataFrame data structure is the heart of the Panda's library.
DataFrame數據結構是Pandas的核心。
It's a primary object that you'll be working with in data analysis
這將是你的主要對象，在處理數據分析
and cleaning tasks.
和數據清理任務的時候。
The DataFrame is conceptually a two-dimensional series object, where
DataFrame在概念上是一個二維列表(series)對象，
there's an index and multiple columns of content, with each column having a label.
其中有一個索引(index)和多列內容，每列(column)都有一個標籤(label)。
In fact, the distinction between a column and
事實上，列(column)和行(row)之間的區別
a row is really only a conceptual distinction.
實際上只是一個概念上的區別。
And you can think of the DataFrame itself as simply a two-axes labeled array.
你可以將DataFrame本身視為簡單的雙軸有標籤的陣列。
You can create a DataFrame in many different ways,
你可以以許多不同的方式創建一個DataFrame，
some of which you might expect.
其中一些你可能想像的到。
For instance, you can use a group of series,
例如，你可以使用一組列表(series)，
where each series represents a row of data.
其中每個列表代表一行數據。
Or you could use a group of dictionaries,
或者你可以使用一組字典(dictionary)，
where each dictionary represents a row of data.
其中每個字典都代表一行數據。
Let's take a look at an example.
我們來看一個例子。
I'm going to create three purchase order records as series objects for
我將創建三個採購訂單記錄作為列表對象。
a sort of fictional store.
在一個虛構的商店。
Each series has a name of a customer,
每個列表都有一個客戶名稱，
the string which describes the item being purchased, and the cost of the items.
描述要購買的商品的字串(string)，以及商品的費用。
I like dogs, so I'll purchase a bunch of dog food.
我喜歡狗，所以我會買一堆狗食。
Kevin Cullens Thompson, the instructor for the third course in the series,
凱文·柯林斯·湯普森，系列中，第三個課程的講師
he seems more like a cat man to me, so I'll have him purchase some kitty litter.
他似乎更像是對我來說，喜歡貓的人，所以我會讓他購買一些貓咪的沙子。
And I think Vinod, who teaches the fourth course in this series,
我認為維諾德，教本系列的第四個課程，
is more of a bird man, so I'll add some bird seed there.
更是一個喜歡鳥的人，所以我會在那裡添加一些鳥吃的種子。
Then we'll feed this into the DataFrame as the first argument and
然後，我們將它們作為第一個參數提供給DataFrame，
set index values indicating which store where each purchase was done.
並設置索引值(index)，代表每個購買的商店。
You'll see that when we print out a DataFrame, the Jupiter notebook's trying
你會看到，當我們打印出一個DataFrame時，Jupyter筆記本試圖
to pretty it up a bit, and print it out as a table, which is nice.
將其漂亮一些，並將其作為表格列印出來，這是很好的。
Similar to the series, we can extract data using the iLock and Lock attributes.
與列表(series)類似，我們可以使用iloc和loc屬性提取數據。
Because the DataFrame is two-dimensional, passing a single value to the lock
因為DataFrame是二維的，所以將單一值傳遞給loc
indexing operator will return series if there's only one row to return.
索引操作將返回一個列表，如果只有一行返回。
In this example, if we wanted to select data associated with Store 2,
在這個例子中，如果我們想要選擇與Store2關聯的數據，
we would just query the lock attribute with one parameter.
那麼我們只用一個參數查詢loc屬性(attribute)。
You'll note that the name of the series is returned as the row index value,
你將注意到，列表的名稱作為行索引值返回，
while the column name is included in the output as well.
而列名(column_name)也包括在輸出中。
We can check the data type of the return using the python type function.
我們可以使用python類型(type)函數檢查返回的數據類型。
It's important to remember that the indices and
重要的是要記住，索引(index)和
column names along either axes, horizontal or vertical, could be non-unique.
列(row)名稱，沿著任何一軸，水平或垂直方向的，可能不必是唯一的。
For instance, in this example, we see two purchase records for
例如，在這個例子中，我們看到兩個採購記錄
Store 1 as different rows.
在Store1是不同的行。
If we use a single value with the DataFrame lock attribute, multiple rows of
如果我們用單一值在DataFrame的loc屬性，多行
the DataFrame will return, not as a new series, but as a new DataFrame.
的DataFrame將返回，不是新的列表，而是新的DataFrame。
For instance, if we query for Store 1 records,
例如，如果我們查詢Store1記錄，
we see that Chris and Kevin both shop at the same pets supply store.
我們會看到Chris和Kevin都在同一個寵物用品商店購物。
One of the powers of the Panda's DataFrame is that you can quickly select data based
Pandas的DataFrame的一個功能，就是可以快速的選擇數據
on multiple axes.
在多重軸上
For instance, if you wanted to just list the costs for Store 1, you would supply
例如，如果你只想列出Store1的費用，你將提供
two parameters to .log, one being the row index and the other being the column name.
兩個參數給.loc，一個為行(row)索引，另一個為列名(column)。
If we're only interested in Store 1 costs, we could write this as df.lock('Store 1',
如果我們只對Store 1的費用感興趣，我們可以把它寫成 df.loc['Store 1',
'Cost').
'Cost']
What if we just wanted to do column selection and
如果我們只想做列(row)選擇，
just get a list of all of the costs?
並且只取所有費用的清單怎麼辦？
Well, there's a couple of options.
那麼有幾個選擇。
First, you can get a transpose of the DataFrame,
首先，你可以首先獲取DataFrame的轉置使用大寫T屬性
using the capital T attribute, which swaps all of the columns and rows.
，該屬性將交換所有列和行。
This essentially turns your column names into indices.
這本質上將你的列名稱變成索引(index)。
And we can then use the .lock method.
然後我們可以使用.loc方法。
This works, but it's pretty ugly.
這是有用的，但它很醜陋。
Since iloc and loc are used for row selection, the Panda's developers
由於iloc和loc用於行(row)的選擇，Pandas的開發人員
reserved indexing operator directly on the DataFrame for column selection.
直接在DataFrame上保留索引操作列(column)的選擇。
In a Panda's DataFrame, columns always have a name.
在Pandas的DataFrame中，列(column)總是有一個名字。
So this selection is always label based, not as confusing as it was when
所以這個選擇始終是基於標籤(label)的，而不是像
using the square bracket operator on the series objects.
在列表(series)對像上使用方括號運算符一樣混亂。
For those familiar with relational databases,
對於那些熟悉關聯資料庫的人來說，
this operator is analogous to column projection.
這個操作類似於列(column)的投影。
Finally, since the result of using the indexing operators,
最後，由於使用索引(indexing)運算的結果
the DataFrame or series, you can chain operations together.
是DataFrame或者series，所以可以將運算鏈接在一起。
For instance, we could have rewritten the query for
例如，我們可以將所有Store 1費用的查詢
all Store 1 costs as df.loc('Store 1', 'Cost').
所有 "Store 1" 的成本是 df.loc('Store 1', 'Cost')
This looks pretty reasonable and gets us the result we wanted.
這看起來相當合理，獲取我們我們想要的結果。
But chaining can come with some costs and
但鏈接可能會帶來一些代價，
is best avoided if you can use another approach.
最好避免，如果可以使用其他方法。
In particular, chaining tends to cause Pandas to return a copy of the DataFrame
特別是，鏈接往往導致 Pandas 返回DataFrame的副本
instead of a view on the DataFrame.
而不是DataFrame的視圖。
For selecting a data,
對於選擇數據，
this is not a big deal, though it might be slower than necessary.
這沒什麼大不了的，儘管它可能比必要的慢一點。
If you are changing data though, this is an important distinction and
如果你正在更改數據，這是一個重要的區別，
can be a source of error.
可能是錯誤的根源。
Here's another method.
這裡是另一種方法。
As we saw, .loc does row selection, and it can take two parameters,
我們看到，.loc執行row的選擇，它可以使用兩個參數，
the row index and the list of column names.
row索引和column名稱列表。
.loc also supports slicing.
.loc也支持分離切片。
If we wanted to select all rows,
如果我們想要選擇所有的row，
we can use a column to indicate a full slice from beginning to end.
我們可以使用一個column，表明從頭到尾一個完整的切片。
And then add the column name as the second parameter as a string.
然後添加column名稱字串，作為第二個參數。
In fact, if we wanted to include multiply columns, we could do so in a list.
實際上，如果我們要包含多幾行columns，我們可以用列表來這樣做。
And Pandas will bring back only the columns we have asked for.
Pandas只會顯示出我們要求的columns。
Here's an example, where we ask for
這裡有一個例子，我們要求
all of the name and cost values for all stores using the .loc operator.
所有商店的名稱和費用，使用.loc運算符。
So that's selecting and projecting data from a DataFrame based on row and
這就是從DataFrame中選擇和投影數據，根據row和
column labels.
column標籤。
The key concepts to remember are that the rows and columns are really just for
要記住的關鍵概念是行和列，真的只是為了
our benefit.
我們的方便使用。
Underneath this is just a two axes labeled array, and
在這裏面只是一個雙軸有標籤的陣列(array)，而且
transposing the columns is easy.
轉置columns是很容易的。
Also, consider the issue of chaining carefully, and
另外，仔細考慮鏈接(chaining)的問題，
try to avoid it, it can cause unpredictable results.
盡量避免，它可能會導致不可預知的結果。
Where your intent was to obtain a view of the data, but
你的意圖是獲取數據的視圖(view)，
instead Pandas returns to you a copy.
而Pandas會返回給你一份副本。
In the Panda's world, friends don't let friends chain calls.
在Pandas的世界裡，做朋友的不要讓朋友用鏈接。
So if you see it, point it out, and share a less ambiguous solution.
所以如果你看到它，指出來，並且分享一個較不模糊的解決方案。
Now, before we leave the discussion of accessing data in DataFrames,
現在，在我們離開討論存取DataFrames中的數據之前，
let's talk about dropping data.
我們來談談刪除數據。
It's easy to delete data in series and DataFrames, and
很容易刪除series和DataFrames的數據，
we can use the drop function to do so.
我們可以使用drop函數來這樣做。
This function takes a single parameter, which is the index or roll label, to drop.
此函數需要單一參數，即索引(index)或row標籤。
This is another tricky place for new users to pad this.
這是Pandas新使用者另一個棘手的地方。
The drop function doesn't change the DataFrame by default.
正規的情況下，drop函數不會更改DataFrame。
And instead, returns to you a copy of the DataFrame with the given rows removed.
相反，返回給你刪除了指定行的DataFrame的副本。
We can see that our original DataFrame is still intact.
我們可以看到，我們原來的DataFrame還是完好無損的。
Let's make a copy with the copy method and do a drop on it instead.
讓我們用copy方法複製一份，然後再用drop函數在這副本。
This is a very typical pattern in Pandas, where in place changes to a DataFrame
在Pandas中，這是一個非常典型的模式，對DataFrame進行就地更改，
are only done if need be, usually on changes involving indices.
只有在需要的時候才能做，通常是在涉及index的變更上。
So it's important to be aware of.
所以重要的是要注意到。
Drop has two interesting optional parameters.
Drop有兩個有趣的可選擇的參數。
The first is called in place, and if it's set to true,
第一個是inplace，如果設置為true，
the DataFrame will be updated in place, instead of a copy being returned.
則DataFrame將被就地更新，而不是返回副本。
The second parameter is the axes, which should be dropped.
第二個參數是axis，表示要刪除的。
By default, this value is 0, indicating the row axes.
正規的情況下，該值為0，表示row的軸向。
But you could change it to 1 if you want to drop a column.
但是，如果要刪除column，則可以將其更改為1。
There is a second way to drop a column, however.
然而，有第二種方法去刪除column。
And that's directly through the use of the indexing operator, using the del keyword.
直接使用索引操作，使用del關鍵字。
This way of dropping data,
但是，丟棄數據的方法
however, takes immediate effect on the DataFrame and does not return a view.
立即對DataFrame生效，並且不返回視圖。
Finally, adding a new column to the DataFrame is
最後，向DataFrame添加一個新column
as easy as assigning it to some value.
與將其指定某些值一樣簡單。
For instance,
比如說，
if we wanted to add a new location as a column with default value of none,
如果我們想要添加一個新的位置作為column，預設值為none，
we could do so by using the assignment operator after the square brackets.
我們可以在方括弧之後，使用指派運算符來實現。
This broadcasts the default value to the new column immediately.
這將立即將預設值放送到新的column。